Guide to the Amado M. Padilla Papers M0497
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 3. National Center for Bilingual Education and Research (NCBR)
  - Longitudinal Language Project
    - Volume 2: Procedures Manual and Guide to the NCBR Longitudinal Study of Language Development in Bilingual Contexts. Romero, Padilla, Garcia, Lindholm, Hoffman, 1984-08 (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Volume 3. Case Studies of Children in the Longitudinal Language Project. Garcia, Kim, Romero, 1984-08 (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Summary of Parent Interviews. Romero, Veyna-Lopez, 1985-04 (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Computer Printouts, 1985-04 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Seminar Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - ESEA Title VII Bilingual Education Program, Bilingual/Bicultural Education Program Reports, by State, 1982-1983
    - Alaska (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Arizona (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - California (Box 62, Folder 7, Box 63, Folders 1-4)
    - Colorado (Box 64, Folder 1)
    - Delaware, Florida (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Georgia, Kansas, Kentucky (Box 64, Folder 3)
    - Maryland (Box 64, Folder 4)
    - Massachusetts (Box 64, Folder 5)
    - Michigan, New Mexico (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - New Jersey (Box 65, Folder 1)
    - New York (Box 65, Folders 2-3)
    - Ohio, Rhode Island (Box 65, Folder 4)
    - Tennessee (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - Texas (Box 66, Folders 2-4)
    - Washington (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Meta-Analysis Project (RFP 81-068. Synthesis of Reported Evaluation and Research Evidence on the Effectiveness of Bilingual Education Basic Projects)
    - NCBR Padilla correspondence 9-12/, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - NCBR Padilla correspondence, 1984 (Box 67, Folders 2-3)
    - State Bilingual Programs, 1981-1982 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Quarterly Report memoranda, 1981-1982 (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Paula Martin Ed. D. Dissertation abstract, 1981 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - N. Gold’s Instrument, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 7)
    - Coding Sheet Draft, 1978 (Box 67, Folder 8)
    - Coder Questionaire, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 9)
    - Field Solicitations, 1982 (Box 67, Folder 10)
    - Meta-Analysis Codes (Box 67, Folder 11)
    - Meta-Analysis Files and Data Cards Listing (Box 67, Folder 12)
    - Meta-Analysis Resource Information, 1983 (Box 67, Folder 13)
    - Dissertation Bibliographic Search, 1980 (Box 67, Folder 14)
    - NCBR correspondence, 1981-1983 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Consultants (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Meta-Analysis Advisory Panel, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - BECES, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Data – BICAL (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Meta-Analysis Deliverables, 1981-1982 (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography Draft (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Tasks (Directories) (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Meta-Analysis Tests (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Responses to A.I.R. Study (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Secretarial Requests, Work Unit Contract 804 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Secretarial Requests, Work Unit Contract 806, 807 (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Blank Coding Forms, etc. (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - D.O.E. Request for Proposal (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Technical Proposal, 1981-08 (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Cost Proposals, 1981 (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Revisions and Clarifications (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Updated Baseline Management Plan, 1981-10 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Preliminary Draft Final Report, 1982-08 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Final Report Tasks 1-6 Draft, 1982-11 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Final Report. Vol. 1 Tasks 1-6 November 1982; Tasks 7-8 July 1983, 1982-1983 (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - punch cards and computer print-outs [unfoldered] (Box 70)
  - Meta-Analysis Project Reports, Coding Sheets, etc.
    - Phase I, 428-458 (Box 73, Box 74, Box 72)
      evaluation and performance reports for various education programs including bilingual projects, memoranda, program descriptions, plans with appendices, charts, etc.
    - Title VII Guide Book: Demo Projects (Box 76, Box 77, Box 78)
    - 1977-1980 Included (Box 88, Box 114, Box 115, Box 113, Box 78, Box 79, Box 87, Box 80, Box 99, Box 100, Box 76, Box 127, Box 74, Box 101, Box 125, Box 75, Box 126)
      Evaluations, tests, data, bilingual meta analysis coding forms and sheets, related documents.
    - 1980-1981 Included (Box 83, Box 123, Box 124, Box 81, Box 82, Box 80)
      Bilingual meta analysis coding forms, etc.
    - 1980-1981 Excluded (Box 84, Box 85, Box 83)
      Reports, programs, bilingual meta analysis coding forms, miscellaneous photocopies, related documents, articles, papers, etc.
    - Phase II, 096-151 (Box 87, Box 85, Box 86)
      Evaluation reports, financial status reports, performance reports, etc.
    - Phase I, 234-272 (Box 90, Box 91, Box 89)
      Evaluation reports, project reports, related documents.
    - 1980-1981 Data and Included Reports (Box 92, Box 93)
      Evaluation reports, bilingual meta analysis coding forms and sheets, instructions, routing sheets, programs, related documents.
    - Early Screening Forms (Box 94)
    - Reliability, Parts 1 and 2 (Box 94)
    - Coded; Excluded; Parts 1 and 2 (Box 94, Box 95)
    - Reliability, T and C, 1982-10 (Box 95)
    - Offline Bibliography, 1980 (Box 95)
    - misc. (Box 98, Box 95, Box 96)
      Photocopies of various documents (resumes, annotated bibliographies, off prints), printouts, reports, bilingual meta analysis coding forms and sheets, "Phase 1" materials, etc.
    - 1980-81, Included and Excluded by State (All Possible) (Box 97)
    - Phase I, 1977-1980, Ordered by State and Within by Grant Number (Box 97)
    - 1980-81, by State Grant Number (All Possible) (Box 97)
    - Phase I, 459-493 (Box 102, Box 103, Box 101)
      Interim reports, evaluation reports, final reports.
    - Phase II, 272-526 (Box 103, Box 106, Box 104, Box 105)
    - Phase I, 400-427 (Box 107, Box 108, Box 106)
      Evaluation reports, final reports, correspondence, etc.
    - Phase I, 303-337 (Box 108, Box 111, Box 109, Box 110)
    - Phase II, 001-097 (Box 112, Box 113, Box 111)
    - Journal Files, 1980-1981 Excluded (Box 115, Box 116, Box 117)
      Bilingual meta analysis coding forms, off prints and photocopies of articles.
    - Phase I, 359-399 (Box 119, Box 120, Box 117, Box 118)
      Final evaluations, correspondence, reports, programs.
    - Interim Reports. Deseq. Project. U.S. Territories (Box 122, Box 123, Box 120, Box 121)
      Interim and evaluation reports, related documents.
    - Phase I, 016-036 (Box 129, Box 130, Box 127, Box 128)
    - Phase I, 01-015 (Box 131, Box 132, Box 130)
    - Phase I, 147-168 (Box 134, Box 132, Box 133)
    - Phase I, 037-061 (Box 136, Box 137, Box 135)
    - Phase I, 338-359 (Box 137, Box 138, Box 139, Box 140)
    - Phase I, 195-233 (Box 140, Box 141, Box 142)
    - Phase I, 089-128 (Box 144, Box 145, Box 143)
    - Phase I, 273-302 (Box 147, Box 148, Box 145, Box 146)
    - Phase I, 129-146 (Box 150, Box 148, Box 149)
    - Phase I, 062-088 (Box 151, Box 152, Box 153)
    - Phase II, 527-620 (Box 153, Box 154, Box 155, Box 156)
    - Phase I, 169-194 (Box 156, Box 157, Box 158, Box 159)
    - Evaluation, performance and financial reports, etc., 1982 (Box 163, Box 164, Box 161, Box 162, Box 166, Box 165, Box 172, Box 167, Box 168, Box 159, Box 160, Box 169)
      Reports, related documents.
    - Project Adelante (Box 166)
    - Demonstration project (Box 167)
    - Data for Decisions - Project Spirit (Box 168)
    - 1981-1982 End-of-year Report (Box 168, Box 169)
    - Elementary Bilingual Language Arts - Annual Report, other reports (Box 170)
    - Project New Land (Box 171)
    - Bienvenido Bilingual Education Project - End-of-Year Report (Box 171)
    - Project Beacon (Box 172)
    - Espanola Public Schools Program (Box 172)
    - Avoyelles Parish School Board (Box 172)
    - misc. NCBR material (Box 174, Box 175, Box 173)
      Quarterly reports, RFP, original proposals, related documents.
    - User's Guides to NCBR Databases (Box 190, Box 191, Box 192)
    - User's Guide to NCBR number 1 Databases, Vol. 1-6 (Box 200, Box 203, Box 204, Box 201, Box 202)
    - User Guides to Number 3, NCBR Data Bases (Box 188, Box 190, Box 189)
    - NCBR number 4, Research Reports no. 1 thru 20 (Box 196, Box 194, Box 195, Box 193)
    - NCBR number 5: Research Reports no. 21-48, Technical Notes no. 1-7 (Box 184, Box 182, Box 183, Box 180, Box 181)
    - NCBR number 6: Professional papers, no. 1-21, Special publications, no. 1-5 (Box 186, Box 187, Box 184, Box 185, Box 188)
    - User's Guide to NCBR Vol. 7-13 (Box 199, Box 200, Box 197, Box 198)
    - NCBR number 7, 1981-1982 (Box 176, Box 179, Box 180, Box 177, Box 178)
    - NCBR number 8 (Box 176, Box 175)
- Series 4. Center for Language Education and Research (CLEAR) correspondence 1986-1987
  - Incoming, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Internal, 1986 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Incoming, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Internal & Other, 1987 (Box 71, Folder 5)